Loneliness.
الوحدة.
All of us in this room will experience loneliness
كلنا في هذه الغرفة سنتعرض للوحدة
at some point in our lives.
في مرحلة معينة من حياتنا.
Loneliness is not a function of being alone,
الوحدة ليست كونك وحيدًا،
but rather, a function of how socially connected you are
وإنما تعبر عن مدى ارتباطك اجتماعيًا
to those around you.
بالأفراد من حولك.
There could be somebody in this room right now
ربما هناك شخص في هذه الغرفة الآن
surrounded by a thousand people
محاط بآلاف من الناس
experiencing loneliness.
يعاني من الشعور بالوحدة.
And while loneliness can be attributed to many things,
وعلى الرغم من أن الوحدة قد ترجع لعدة أسباب،
as an architect,
كمهندسة معمارية،
I'm going to tell you today how loneliness can be the result
سأخبركم كيف يمكن للوحدة أن تكون نتيجة
of our built environments --
لبيئتنا المبنية --
the very homes we choose to live in.
البيوت التي نختار العيش فيها.
Let's take a look at this house.
انظر إلى هذا المنزل.
It's a nice house.
إنه منزل لطيف.
There's a big yard, picket fence,
بساحة كبيرة، وسياج خشبي،
two-car garage.
مرآبين للسيارات.
And the home might be in a neighborhood like this.
والمنزل قد يكون في حي مثل هذا.
And for many people around the globe,
وبالنسبة لكثير من الناس في العالم،
this home, this neighborhood --
هذا المنزل، هذا الحي --
it's a dream.
هو حُلم.
And yet the danger of achieving this dream
ولكن خطر تحقيق هذا الحلم
is a false sense of connection
هو إحساس خادع بالاتصال
and an increase in social isolation.
وزيادة في العزلة الاجتماعية.
I know, I can hear you now,
أعرف، أستطيع سماعكم الآن،
there's somebody in the room screaming at me inside their head,
شخص في هذه الغرفة ينفعل عليّ في عقله،
"That's my house, and that's my neighborhood,
"هذا منزلي، هذا حيي الخاص،
and I know everyone on my block!"
وأعرف كل شخص فيه!"
To which I would answer, "Terrific!"
وسأرد عليه، "عظيم!"
And I wish there were more people like you,
وأتمنى أن يكون هناك الكثير من الناس مثلك،
because I'd wager to guess there's more people in the room
لأني أراهن أن كثير من الناس في الغرفة
living in a similar situation
يعيشون في موقف مشابه
that might not know their neighbors.
ولا يعرفون على الأغلب جيرانهم.
They might recognize them and say hello,
يمكنهم التعرف عليهم والترحيب بهم،
but under their breath,
ولكن في أنفسهم،
they're asking their spouse,
يسألون أقرانهم،
"What was their name again?"
"عفوًا ماذا كانت أسماؤهم؟"
so they can ask a question by name to signify they know them.
ليتمكنوا من أن يسألونهم سؤالًا بالاسم كدلالة على معرفتهم.
Social media also contributes to this false sense of connection.
مواقع التواصل الاجتماعي تساهم أيضًا في هذا الإحساس الخادع بالتواصل.
This image is probably all too familiar.
هذه الصورة مألوفة جدًا.
You're standing in the elevator,
تقف في المصعد،
sitting in a cafe,
تجلس في مقهى،
and you look around,
وتنظر حولك،
and everyone's on their phone.
وكل شخص مشغول بهاتفه.
You're not texting or checking Facebook,
أنت لا تراسل أو تتابع الفيسبوك،
but everyone else is,
ولكن الآخرين يفعلون ذلك.
and maybe, like me, you've been in a situation
وربما، مثلي، تكون في موقف
where you've made eye contact,
تقوم فيه بالاتصال البصري،
smiled and said hello,
تبتسم وترحب،
and have that person yank out their earbuds
وتجد الشخص أمامك يخرج سماعات أذنه
and say, "I'm sorry, what did you say?"
ويقول، "آسف، ماذا قلت؟"
I find this incredibly isolating.
وأجد أن ذلك مسبب كبير للانعزال.
The concept I'd like to share with you today
المفهوم الذي أود مشاركته اليوم معكم
is an antidote to isolation.
هو علاج للانعزال.
It's not a new concept.
إنه ليس مفهومًا جديدًا.
In fact, it's an age-old way of living,
في الواقع، إنها طريقة قديمة للعيش،
and it still exists in many non-European cultures
ومستمرة الآن في العديد من الثقافات غير الأوروبية
around the world.
حول العالم.
And about 50 years ago,
وقبل حوالي 50 عامًا،
the Danes decided to make up a new name,
قرر الدنماركيون أن يؤلفوا اسمًا جديدًا،
and since then,
ومنذ ذلك الحين،
tens of thousands of Danish people have been living in this connected way.
عشرات آلاف الدنماركيين يعيشون بهذه الطريقة المترابطة.
And it's being pursued more widely around the globe
ويتم اتباع هذه الطريقة بطريقة واسعة حول العالم
as people are seeking community.
لأن الأفراد يبحثون عن التواصل.
This concept
هذا المفهوم هو
is cohousing.
السكن المشترك.
Cohousing is an intentional neighborhood where people know each other
السكن المشترك هو حي دولي حيث يعرف الأفراد بعضهم
and look after one another.
ويهتمون ببعضهم البعض.
In cohousing, you have your own home,
في السكن المشترك، كل فرد لديه منزله الخاص،
but you also share significant spaces, both indoors and out.
ولكنهم يتقاسمون أماكن كبيرة، سواء داخل أو خارج المنزل.
Before I show you some pictures of cohousing,
قبل أن أريكم بعض الصور عن السكن المشترك،
I'd like to first introduce you to my friends Sheila and Spencer.
أود أن أقدم لكم أصدقائي شيلا وسبنسر.
When I first met Sheila and Spencer, they were just entering their 60s,
حين قابلت شيلا وسبنسر لأول مرة، كانوا في بداية الستين،
and Spencer was looking ahead at the end of a long career
وكان سبنسر يتطلع للمستقبل في نهاية مهنة طويلة
in elementary education.
في التعليم الابتدائي.
And he really disliked the idea
وكان يكره فكرة أنه
that he might not have children in his life
من المحتمل ألا ينجب أطفالًا في حياته
upon retirement.
عند التقاعد.
They're now my neighbors.
الآن هم جيراني.
We live in a cohousing community that I not only designed,
نعيش في مجتمع إسكاني مشترك لم أصممه فقط،
but developed
ولكنني طورتُه
and have my architecture practice in.
ومارست فيه قدراتي المعمارية.
This community is very intentional about our social interactions.
هذا المجتمع يدور فعلًا حول تفاعلاتنا الاجتماعية.
So let me take you on a tour.
لذا أود أن آخذكم في جولة.
From the outside, we look like any other small apartment building.
من الخارج، يبدو أشبه بأي مبنى سكني صغير.
In fact, we look identical to the one next door,
في الواقع، يبدو منزلنا مطابقًا للمنزل المجاور،
except that we're bright yellow.
فيما عدا أن لون البناء أصفر ساطع.
Inside, the homes are fairly conventional.
من الداخل، المنازل تقليدية إلي حد بعيد.
We all have living rooms and kitchens,
جميعنا لديه غرف معيشة، مطابخ،
bedrooms and baths,
غرف نوم، وحمامات،
and there are nine of these homes around a central courtyard.
وهناك تسعة من هذه المنازل متمركزة حول ساحة منزل مركزية.
This one's mine,
هذا منزلي،
and this one is Spencer and Sheila's.
وهذا منزل سبنسر وشيلا.
The thing that makes this building uniquely cohousing
وما يجعل هذا المبنى سكنًا مشتركًا مميزًا
are not the homes,
ليس المنازل بحد ذاتِها،
but rather, what happens here --
ولكن، ما يحدث هنا --
the social interactions that happen in and around that central courtyard.
أي التفاعل الاجتماعي الذي يحدث في ساحة المنازل المركزية وحولها.
When I look across the courtyard,
حين أنظر إلي الساحة،
I look forward to see Spencer and Sheila.
أتطلع إلي رؤية سبنسر وشيلا.
In fact, every morning, this is what I see,
وفي الواقع، هذا ما أراه كل صباح،
Spencer waving at me furiously as we're making our breakfasts.
سبنسر يلوِّح لي في حين أن كلًا منا يجهز إفطاره.
From our homes, we look down into the courtyard,
ننظر مباشرة إلي الساحة من منزلنا،
and depending on the time of year,
واعتمادًا على وقت السنة،
we see this:
فقد نرى هذا:
kids and grownups in various combinations
الصغار والشباب في مجموعات متنوعة
playing and hanging out with each other.
يلعبون ويخرجون مع بعضهم.
There's a lot of giggling and chatter.
هناك الكثير من الضحك والثرثرة.
There's a lot of hula-hooping.
وكثير من اللعب.
And every now and then, "Hey, quit hitting me!"
وبين الحين والآخر نسمع، "توقف عن ضربي!"
or a cry from one of the kids.
أو بكاءً من أحد الأطفال.
These are the sounds of our daily lives,
هذه أصوات من حياتنا اليومية،
and the sounds of social connectedness.
وأصوات الترابط الاجتماعي.
At the bottom of the courtyard, there are a set of double doors,
في أسفل الساحة، هناك مجموعة من الأبواب المزدوجة،
and those lead into the common house.
وجميع هذه الأبواب تؤدي إلي المنزل المشترك.
I consider the common house the secret sauce of cohousing.
أعتبر المنزل المشترك هو الخلطة السرية للسكن المشترك.
It's the secret sauce
هو الخلطة السرية
because it's the place where the social interactions
لأنه المكان حيث تبدأ فيه التفاعلات الاجتماعية
and community life begin,
وحياة المجتمع،
and from there, it radiates out through the rest of the community.
ومن هناك، فإنها تنتشر إلى باقي المجتمع.
Inside our common house, we have a large dining room
بداخل المنزل المشترك لدينا غرفة طعام واسعة
to seat all 28 of us and our guests,
لتكفي 28 شخص منا وضيوفنا،
and we dine together three times a week.
ونتناول العشاء سوياً ثلاث مرات في الأسبوع.
In support of those meals, we have a large kitchen
من أجل تجهيز تلك الوجبات، لدينا مطبخ كبير
so that we can take turns cooking for each other
حيث نتبادل فيه الأدوار في الطبخ
in teams of three.
في فرق من ثلاث أفراد.
So that means, with 17 adults,
وهذا يعني، بوجود 17 شخص بالغ،
I lead cook once every six weeks.
فأنا أقود الطهي مرة كل 6 أسابيع.
Two other times, I show up and help my team
مرتين أخرتين، أحضر وأساعد فريقي
with the preparation and cleanup.
في التحضير والتنظيف.
And all those other nights,
وفي الليالي الأخرى،
I just show up.
فأنا أحضر فقط.
I have dinner, talk with my neighbors,
أتناول العشاء، أتحدث إلى جيراني،
and I go home, having been fed a delicious meal
وأذهب للمنزل، بعد تناول الوجبة الشهية
by someone who cares about my vegetarian preferences.
التي أعدها شخص أخر يهتم بتفضيلاتي النباتية.
Our nine families have intentionally chosen
عائلاتنا التسعة اختارت عن عمد
an alternative way of living.
طريقة أخرى بديلة للحياة.
Instead of pursuing the American dream,
بدلاً من السعي وراء الحلم الأمريكي،
where we might have been isolated in our single-family homes,
والذي ربما بسببه نكون معزولين في منازلنا ذات العائلة الواحدة،
we instead chose cohousing,
فنحن نختار السكن المشترك،
so that we can increase our social connections.
حيث يمكننا زيادة العلاقات الاجتماعية.
And that's how cohousing starts:
وهذه هي طريقة بداية السكن المشترك:
with a shared intention
بنية مشتركة
to live collaboratively.
للعيش بتعاون.
And intention is the single most important characteristic
والنية هي الصفة الأهم
that differentiates cohousing from any other housing model.
والتي تميز السكن المشترك عن أي نموذج آخر من السكن.
And while intention is difficult to see
وبالرغم من أن النية صعب أن تُرى
or even show,
أو حتى أن تظهر،
I'm an architect, and I can't help but show you more pictures.
أنا مهندسة معمارية، ولا يمكنني إلا أن أريكم مزيداً من الصور.
So here are a few examples to illustrate
وهذه بعض الأمثلة للتوضيح
how intention has been expressed
كيف يمكن للنية أن تظهر
in some of the communities I've visited.
في بعض من المجتمعات التي قمت بزيارتها.
Through the careful selection of furniture,
من خلال الإختيار الحذر للأثاث،
lighting and acoustic materials to support eating together;
والضوء والمواد الصوتية لتدعيم الأكل سوياً
in the careful visual location and visual access
في الموقع البصري الدقيق والتواصُل البصري،
to kids' play areas around and inside the common house;
لأماكن لهو الأطفال وبداخل المنزل المشترك،
in the consideration of scale
مع مراعاة مقياس
and distribution of social gathering nodes
وتوزيع نقاط الالتقاء الاجتماعي
in and around the community to support our daily lives,
بداخل وحول مجتمعنا لتدعيم حياتنا اليومية.
all of these spaces help contribute to and elevate
كل هذه الأماكن تساهم وتزيد
the sense of communitas
من إحساس روح المجتمع
in each community.
في كل مجتمع.
What was that word? "Communitas."
ماذا تعني هذه الكلمة ؟ "Communitas."
Communitas is a fancy social science way of saying "spirit of community."
هي كلمة معقدة علمية إجتماعية لطرح كلمة "روح المجتمع."
And in visiting over 80 different communities,
وخلال زيارتي لأكثر من 80 مجتمع مختلف،
my measure of communitas became:
مقياسي "لروح المجتمع" أصبح:
How frequently did residents eat together?
كم مرة يأكل السكان سوياً؟
While it's completely up to each group
وعلى الرغم من أن الأمر يتوقف على كل مجموعة
how frequently they have common meals,
في عدد المرات لتناول الوجبات المشتركة،
I know some that have eaten together every single night
فأنا أعرف أشخاصاً يأكلون سوياً كل ليلة
for the past 40 years.
في الأربعين سنة الماضية.
I know others
وأعرف آخرين
that have an occasional potluck once or twice a month.
يتناولون بعض الطعام مرة أو مرتين في الشهر.
And from my observations, I can tell you,
ومن خلاال ملاحظاتي، يمكن أن أخبركم،
those that eat together more frequently,
هؤلاء الذين يأكلون سوياً بشكل متكرر،
exhibit higher levels of communitas.
لديتهم مستوى عال من "روح المجتمع".
It turns out, when you eat together,
اتضح أنه حين تأكلون سوياً،
you start planning more activities together.
فإنكم تخططون لأنشطة أخرى سوياً.
When you eat together, you share more things.
حين تأكلون سوياً، فأنكم تشاركون أشياء أكثر.
You start to watch each other's kids.
فتبدأون بملاحظة أطفال بعضكم.
You lend our your power tools. You borrow each other's cars.
فتشاركون بعضكم أدوات السُلطة. وكل منكم يستعير سيارة الآخر.
And despite all this,
وعلى الرغم من كل ذلك،
as my daughter loves to say,
إبنتي تحب دوماً أن تقول،
everything is not rainbows and unicorns in cohousing,
ليس كل شيء فائق المتعة في السكن المشترك،
and I'm not best friends with every single person in my community.
وأنا لست أفضل صديق لكل شخص لمجتمعي.
We even have differences and conflicts.
فلدينا بعض الاختلافات والصراعات.
But living in cohousing, we're intentional about our relationships.
ولكن العيش في السكن المشترك، يتطلب أن تكون علاقاتنا لها مقصد.
We're motivated to resolve our differences.
فلدينا دوافع لحل اختلافاتنا.
We follow up, we check in,
فنحن نتابع، ونفحص،
we speak our personal truths
نتحدث بحقائقنا الشخصية،
and, when appropriate,
وإذا لزم الأمر،
we apologize.
فإننا نعتذر.
Skeptics will say that cohousing is only interesting or attractive
المتشككون سيقولون أن السكن المشترك جذاب ومشوق
to a very small group of people.
لمجموعة صغيرة فقط من الناس.
And I'll agree with that.
وأنا أوافق هذا الرأي تماماً،
If you look at Western cultures around the globe,
إذا نظرت إلى الثقافة الغربية حول العالم،
those living in cohousing are just a fractional percent.
فهؤلاء الذين يعيشون في سكن مشترك يمثلون نسبة ضئيلة.
But that needs to change,
ولكن هذا بحاجة إلى أن يتغير،
because our very lives depend upon it.
لأن حياتنا تعتمد كلياً عليه.
In 2015, Brigham Young University completed a study
في 2015، أكملت جامعة بريغهام يونغ
that showed a significant increase risk of premature death
دراسة تبين مخاطر الزيادة الكبيرة للموت المبكر
in those who were living in isolation.
للأفراد الذين يعيشون في عزلة.
The US Surgeon General has declared isolation
جراح الولايات المتحدة العام صنف الإنعزال
to be a public health epidemic.
بوباء الصحة العامة.
And this epidemic is not restricted to the US alone.
وهذا الوباء ليس مقصوراً على الولايات المتحدة وحدها.
So when I said earlier
وكما قلت من قبل
that cohousing is an antidote to isolation,
بأن السكن المشترك هو ترياق للإنعزال،
what I should have said
ما كان يجب عليَ قوله
is that cohousing can save your life.
هو أن السكن المشترك قد ينقذ حياتك.
If I was a doctor, I would tell you to take two aspirin,
لو كنت طبيبة، فسأنصحك بتناول قرصين من الاسبيرين،
and call me in the morning.
والإتصال بي في الصباح.
But as an architect,
ولكن كمهندسة معمارية،
I'm going to suggest that you take a walk with your neighbor,
فسأقترح أن تأخذ نزهة سير مع جارك،
share a meal together,
وتناول وجبة سوياً،
and call me in 20 years.
واتصل بي بعد 20 سنة.
Thank you.
شكراً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)